

# Gnana prahaasam

**MERN Stack Developer** 

# Contact



+91 7904431901



srgnanaprahaasam@gmail.com



937, Paraiyur, thungavi Post, Madathukulam -642203



https://www.linkedin.com/in/gnanaprahaasam-sr

## **About Me**

I'm a software developer with two years of experience in web application development, specializing in building scalable and secure applications using React.js, Express.js, and Node.js, with MongoDB for database management. I have been actively involved in all stages of the development process, from requirement gathering architecture design to deployment.

# ₩ Skills

- React.js | Express.js
- JavaScript | TypeScript
- MongoDB | MYSQL
- Redux | Redux Toolkit
- HTML | Css | Bootstrap
- SPFX | SharePoint
- GitHub
- Core Java



# **Experience**

#### **Software Developer**

2023 - present

I have experience in developing web applications and SharePoint applications (SPFx) using the MEAR stack. I am proficient in building secure and scalable REST APIs and have expertise in Git version control, along with deployment knowledge on AWS and Hostinger VPS environments.

### **Technology Trainer**

2021 - 2022

I have one year of experience as a technology trainer in web development and programming, including internship expertise.

### Education

### **Master of Computer Application**

Dr. mahalingam college of Engineering and Technology.

2021 - 2023 (CGPA 7.8)

#### **Bachelor of Mathematics**

Government Arts and Science college.

2017 - 2020 (CGPA 7.7)



# **Projects**

## **KidsQatar**

(React.js, Express.js, Node.js & MongoDB , AWS )

- Designed as a search engine, it provides detailed information on schools, extracurricular activities, sports, entertainment, events, libraries, and doctors, helping parents in Qatar easily find quality services for their children.
- Implemented JWT for user authentication and integrated Amazon S3 for dynamic asset storage.
- Developed scalable and secure REST APIs, deployed on AWS EC2 for reliability and performance.

#### **POAM**

(React.js, SPFX, TypeScript, Pnp.js, App Catalog)

- I contributed to the entire development process of an application using the SharePoint Framework (SPFx) to streamline procurement and travel management processes.
- It enables seamless request submission, approval workflows, and tracking of approval status for both purchase and travel requests.
- It is securely integrated with the office domain using PnP/JS for REST API communication, ensuring efficient data connectivity with SharePoint.

#### Siri Hr Consultant

(HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, js, AWS)

- · It is static website for an HR consulting service company offering expert solutions for recruitment and workforce management.
- I have developed a responsive static website using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap to showcase services with a professional and user-friendly interface. It is hosted on AWS using S3 Bucket, Route 53, ACM, and CloudFront.